Guide to the Maurice Francis Egan Letters
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Maurice Francis Egan Letters,
1911-1919.
Egan, Maurice Francis, 1852-1924.
32 (1 box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078729
Biographical Note
American short story writer, envoy to Denmark.
Scope and Content
Letters from Egan to Henry Goddard Leach. These concern the stories and poems of both men, United States-Scandinavian affairs, President Wilson, Danish theater and literature, and the effect on Denmark of the American embargo during the first World War.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series:
Series I: Correspondence, Ougoing, 1911-1919
Series II: Correspondence, Incoming, 1917-1918
Series III: General, 1911-1916
Subjects
Leach, Henry Goddard, 1800-1970.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; United States--Foreign relations--Denmark.; Denmark--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Scandinavia.; Scandinavia--Foreign relations--United States.; Denmark--Social life and customs.; Denmark--Politics and government.; Denmark--Economic conditions.; World War, 1914-1918--Denmark.; American poetry--20th century.; Theater--Denmark.; Danish literature.; Arts--Denmark.; Authors, American.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1959 M-59 41568P
- Series I: Correspondence, Outgoing, 1911-1919
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
    - undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1911 July 6 (Box 1)
    - 1912 June 4 (Box 1)
    - 1913 May 5 (Box 1)
    - 1913 May 28 (Box 1)
    - 1913 June 2 (Box 1)
    - 1913 July 7 (Box 1)
    - 1914 October 10 (Box 1)
    - 1914 November 19 (Box 1)
    - 1915 February 4 (Box 1)
    - 1915 April 28 (Box 1)
    - 1917 June 26 (Box 1)
    - 1918 February 10 (Box 1)
    - 1918 May 6 (Box 1)
    - 1918 May 10 (Box 1)
    - 1918 May 14 (Box 1)
    - 1918 June 4 (Box 1)
    - 1918 July 17 (Box 1)
    - 1918 September 21 (Box 1)
    - 1918 October 10 (Box 1)
    - 1918 October 26 (Box 1)
    - 1919 September 4 (Box 1)
    - 1919 November 25 (Box 1)
    - 1919 December 8 (Box 1)
    - 1919 December 27 (Box 1)
- Series II: Correspondence, Incoming, 1917-1918
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
    - undated (Box 1)
    - 1917 August 8 (Box 1)
    - 1918 September 26 (Box 1)
- Series III: General, 1911-1916
  - Clippings, undated (Box 1)
  - Egan, Carmel--Wedding Invitation, 1911 December 2 (Box 1)
  - Egan, Maurice Francis--Rosenfeld (sonnet), 1916 (Box 1)
  - Lenham, Charles Trueman--Maurice Francis Egan (poem), undated (Box 1)